<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Ficons</title>
  <icon>https://www.gravatar.com/avatar/e5048e048eb572231ac5739e766f17a3</icon>
  <subtitle>Ficons</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://ficons.fiction.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-11-14T16:15:16.192Z</updated>
  <id>https://ficons.fiction.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Fiction.com</name>
    <email>hello@fiction.com</email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Wear Black Clothes</title>
    <link href="https://ficons.fiction.com/2016/11/10/wear-black-clothes/"/>
    <id>https://ficons.fiction.com/2016/11/10/wear-black-clothes/</id>
    <published>2016-11-10T21:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-14T16:15:16.192Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this post I’m going to give you what I consider the best greatest yet simplest (<em>and life</em>) hack of the century: wear black clothes.</p><p>Now, you might say: “Why on earth is wearing black revolutionary? I love my multicolored attire.” Well, just let me show you how much black clothing can simplify and improve your travel life.</p><h1 id="It-means-traveling-with-less-stuff"><a href="#It-means-traveling-with-less-stuff" class="headerlink" title="It means traveling with less stuff"></a>It means traveling with less stuff</h1><p>When I decided to start traveling full time about a year and a half ago, the first thing I did was buy a massive bag, large enough to pack a fat 14 year old child.  I perceived I would need to store my months long supply of clothes and other accessories.</p><p>However, when y0u travel a lot, a big bag like this is a pain. You have to wait in lines, it gets lost, you have to pay fees, etc… I realized I needed to go to the ‘carry on’ only model,  but how?  That’s right, I got rid of the brown shoes, blue pants, multicolored shirts, etc… black always matches black.</p><p><img src="./packing.jpg" alt=""><br><em>Does your bag fit a child?</em></p><h1 id="Blue-jeans-are-ugly-Brown-shoes-are-pointless"><a href="#Blue-jeans-are-ugly-Brown-shoes-are-pointless" class="headerlink" title="Blue jeans are ugly. Brown shoes are pointless."></a>Blue jeans are ugly. Brown shoes are pointless.</h1><p>In this bag I had black and brown shoes, black and blue pants, etc… First, let me ask you… why does everyone wear blue jeans?  Why blue?  I contend that black jeans will always be better than blue. You can wear black jeans to formal as well as casual events, black jeans look great with most colors while blue doesn’t.  That’s right, people wear blue just because that’s what everyone else does.</p><p><img src="./Super-Man-in-Jeans.jpg" alt=""><br><em>Blue jeans must be stopped</em></p><h1 id="It-simplifies-your-life"><a href="#It-simplifies-your-life" class="headerlink" title="It simplifies your life"></a>It simplifies your life</h1><p>Black matches black, and most importantly, no one notices if you were the same thing multiple times.</p><p>That’s right. You can wear the same shirt two days in a row, no one notices. Same shoes, jacket, etc… it doesn’t matter. The same thing doesn’t apply for different color clothing. Wear that striped blue shirt two days in a row and you will be the laughing stock of your neighborhood.</p><p>So stop playing the whole “you need to wear something different every day,” or the “you can only wear these shoes with this color shirt” game that the fashion companies continually push in an effort to sell more clothes.</p><h1 id="It-doesn’t-get-dirty"><a href="#It-doesn’t-get-dirty" class="headerlink" title="It doesn’t get dirty"></a>It doesn’t get dirty</h1><p>Black clothing is really hard to get dirty. Coffee stain? What coffee stain.</p><p>This means you can wear black shoes and clothing for longer before they start to look old and worn out. Perfect for us nomads.</p><p>One caveat, you still have to worry about is cats. I can verify that cat hair and black clothes can still be a problem.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      In this post I’m going to give you what I consider the best greatest yet simplest (and life) hack of...
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="wear-black-clothes" scheme="https://ficons.fiction.com/categories/wear-black-clothes/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Beginner Mindset</title>
    <link href="https://ficons.fiction.com/2015/12/02/the-beginner-mindset/"/>
    <id>https://ficons.fiction.com/2015/12/02/the-beginner-mindset/</id>
    <published>2015-12-02T21:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-14T16:15:16.183Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Do you have a “closed” state of mind?</p></blockquote><p><strong>“Zen” is derived from an ancient word meaning absorption.</strong></p><!-- block --><p>So you might say that Zen is the art of <em>putting yourself in an absorptive state</em>. Or in other words, having a mindset that <em>allows you to be open</em>.<br><!-- block --></p><p>So what does “being open” mean?</p><p>Well, it means removing the unnecessary and unimportant from your life to make way for the new.</p><p>Reducing the clutter that prevents you from focusing on what’s really important.</p><p><strong><em>Now think about it…</em></strong></p><p>Do you have any anchors that prevent you from experiencing or trying new things?</p><p>Do the friends you already have prevent you from seeking out new connections?</p><p>It’s the age old “good is the enemy of great” scenario.</p><p>So how can we improve?</p><h1 id="Zen-Techniques"><a href="#Zen-Techniques" class="headerlink" title="Zen Techniques"></a>Zen Techniques</h1><h2 id="Beginner’s-Mindset"><a href="#Beginner’s-Mindset" class="headerlink" title="Beginner’s Mindset"></a>Beginner’s Mindset</h2><p>As you become more experienced in something, your mind builds set pathways for <em>“the way things are.”</em></p><p>That is, your mind builds experience from pattern matching.</p><p>Over time, the mind relaxes and falls into a state of automation based on these patterns. And while most the time this is a good thing, sometimes it isn’t.</p><p>Pattern matching frees your mind using automation, but over time, patterns can change.</p><p>So to find happiness and success in a changing world, it often requires you adopt a beginner’s mindset.</p><p>Build your patterns based both what you learned when you were younger, but maintain a Zen beginner’s mindset to allow you to create new ones.</p><blockquote><p>Everything that was old, allow it to become new again.</p></blockquote><h1 id="Minimalism"><a href="#Minimalism" class="headerlink" title="Minimalism"></a>Minimalism</h1><p><br><em>Minimizing Focuses You</em></p><p>If your life is already full of objects, you don’t have the space to put anything new.</p><p>If you already have a lot of relationships, you won’t make the effort to really build strong new ones.</p><p>This prevents you from improving. This prevents you from getting better.</p><p><em>And this is why minimalism is a key ingredient in the zen mindset.</em></p><p>and that’s the misconception about minimalism.</p><p>Most think its about “not having,” but in reality it’s about creating the ability to focus and improve.</p><p>If something in your life is unneeded, remove it.  This makes way for new people, more efficient tools.</p><p>So what can you remove?</p><p>Well do you actually need a car or do you just need one to get to work?<br>Do you need to go to work or do you just need to go to work to pay for your car?<br>Maybe you don’t need either.</p><blockquote><p>Possessions are often circular logic.</p></blockquote><div class="instagram-wrapper"><blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px auto; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:8px;"> <div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"> <div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"></div></div><p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/-A038vx6E_/" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank"></a></p></div></blockquote></div><script async defer src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"></script>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
Do you have a &#39;closed&#39; state of mind?

&#39;Zen&#39; is derived from an ancient word meaning absorption.

So you might say that...
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="the-beginner-mindset" scheme="https://ficons.fiction.com/categories/the-beginner-mindset/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Math And The Nomad Movement</title>
    <link href="https://ficons.fiction.com/2015/11/20/math-and-the-nomad-movement/"/>
    <id>https://ficons.fiction.com/2015/11/20/math-and-the-nomad-movement/</id>
    <published>2015-11-20T21:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-14T16:15:16.178Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="The-Math"><a href="#The-Math" class="headerlink" title="The Math"></a>The Math</h1><!-- block --><p>Over the last 5 years I have been living in San Francisco paying over $3000/mo for a one bedroom apartment.<!-- block --> (And this is before the bubble, the same spot is now $4000/mo).</p><p>If you break that down its around $125/ni for a room that I am committed to living in and paying for.</p><p>Since I love to travel, i was ALSO traveling around 50% of the time, paying for hotels. At an average of $150/ni for hotels this means overall I was paying $3000 + 15*150 = $5250 a month for places to sleep.</p><p>Now suppose I remove the apartment from the equation, and just live in hotels. That is $150*30 = $4500/mo.</p><p>So now by living in hotels, I’m actually saving $750/mo and I don’t have to deal with a landlord, I have complete location independence and the services associated with staying at hotels.</p><p>Isn’t this a no brainer?</p><h1 id="The-Technology"><a href="#The-Technology" class="headerlink" title="The Technology"></a>The Technology</h1><p>Over the last 5 to 10 years, we’ve seen a lot of new technology all centered around mobile networking, communication and services. For example: Uber, AirBNB, Facebook, Slack, etc…</p><p>And as I see it, they have made it possible, for the first time ever, for people to live and work independently of any one location.</p><p>For example, pre 2005 visiting new places took a lot of careful planning to avoid the friction associated with transportation, communication, lodging, etc.. but today I can find and/or order anything i need in 30 seconds with my phone.</p><p>Overall, this all makes it very easy to travel to new places and work in them as well.</p><p>Another hurdle to traveling removed?</p><h1 id="The-Movement"><a href="#The-Movement" class="headerlink" title="The Movement"></a>The Movement</h1><p>Because the math just makes sense, I’ve now gone more-or-less fully “nomad.” This means I travel full time.</p><p>I believe that this will be a much bigger thing in the future and it just needs a little leadership.</p><div class="instagram-wrapper"><blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px auto; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:8px;"> <div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"> <div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"></div></div><p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/-J5qJLR6Jb/" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank"></a></p></div></blockquote></div><script async defer src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"></script>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      The Math
Over the last 5 years I have been living in San Francisco paying over $3000/mo for a one bedroom...
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="math-and-the-nomad-movement" scheme="https://ficons.fiction.com/categories/math-and-the-nomad-movement/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Applied Socratic Method</title>
    <link href="https://ficons.fiction.com/2014/12/02/applied-socratic-method/"/>
    <id>https://ficons.fiction.com/2014/12/02/applied-socratic-method/</id>
    <published>2014-12-02T15:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-14T16:15:16.178Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since you were in high school, you’ve probably heard about Socrates and his infamous “Socratic Method.” <a id="more"></a> But if you’re anything like me, you probably don’t know that much about it. Maybe that it means asking questions to prove a point, but that’s not the whole story.</p><p>Recently, I noticed that so many great minds pay homage to the works of Socrates. For example, Benjamin Franklin explicitly stated that his goal was to be more like Socrates. So I did some reading, and found a lot of interesting ideas and principles.</p><p>Socratic method is a much deeper and more conceptual way of thinking than I realized, and it’s already making an important difference in the way I think and act..</p><h1 id="What’s-the-Point"><a href="#What’s-the-Point" class="headerlink" title="What’s the Point?"></a>What’s the Point?</h1><blockquote><p>“I can’t teach anybody anything, I can only make them think.”<br>– Socrates</p></blockquote><p>The point of using Socrates method is that it is one of the best ways to either move someone toward your line of thinking; or improve their thinking in general about a subject.</p><p>The objective is to get someone to think. To get them to potentially reconsider a set way of thinking.</p><p>Perhaps the most interesting thing about Socratic method, is that it works. This concept has the power to move mountains. You can resolve conflicts, make sales, get better results and more if you master it. But mastering it isn’t easy, it takes practice.</p><p>So let’s go through some of the underlying concepts.</p><h1 id="Concept-1-I-Don’t-Know-You-Don’t-Either"><a href="#Concept-1-I-Don’t-Know-You-Don’t-Either" class="headerlink" title="Concept 1. I Don’t Know, You Don’t Either"></a>Concept 1. I Don’t Know, You Don’t Either</h1><blockquote><p>I am wiser than this man, for neither of us appears to know anything great or good; but he fancies he knows something, although he knows nothing; whereas I, as I do not know anything, so I do not fancy I do.”<br>– Socrates</p></blockquote><p>The foundation to Socrates’ method of thinking was first based on his assumption that he “knew nothing.”  In effect, this meant that he started every conversation on the basis that he knew nothing about the subject being discussed.</p><p>While he may, or may not, have actually thought that he knew something. This assumption put him at an important, and subtle, advantage in his conversation.</p><p>When you admit you know nothing, you can’t be argued with. You can only be taught.</p><h1 id="Concept-2-Ask-“Yes”-Questions"><a href="#Concept-2-Ask-“Yes”-Questions" class="headerlink" title="Concept 2. Ask “Yes” Questions"></a>Concept 2. Ask “Yes” Questions</h1><p>Assuming that you “don’t know anything” becomes this basis for asking pointed questions, getting people to explain their viewpoint.</p><p>Questions tend to invoke a response, and if you ask the right questions, that response will require thinking.</p><p>What type of questions? Typically, you always want to start with “yes” questions. These are questions that confirm the assumptions of your counterpart.</p><p>Once you get someone to confirm their starting belief, your next move is to draw logical conclusions based on them.  And then, once you get the person to agree with those next conclusions, draw more conclusions.</p><p>At some point, you will have exhausted all preconceived notions for the argument and your counterpart will need to do actual consideration to answer you.</p><p>This process of getting someone to open up their mind is where the persuasive power of Socrates lies.</p><h1 id="Concept-3-Read-amp-Practice"><a href="#Concept-3-Read-amp-Practice" class="headerlink" title="Concept 3. Read &amp; Practice"></a>Concept 3. Read &amp; Practice</h1><p>The art of Socratic method is extremely powerful in nearly all aspects of your life. But to do it effectively takes practice.  I also haven’t done any real justice into the way it’s done with this article. So I can only point you in the right direction.</p><p>I recommend you read some of the works of Socrates in these books, and see for yourself how it worked. The books I recommend:</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Conversations-Socrates-Classics-Xenophon-ebook/dp/B002RI94JG/" target="_blank" rel="external">Conversations With Socrates</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Trial-Death-Socrates-Dialogues-Editions-ebook/dp/B008TVLOZM/" target="_blank" rel="external">The Trial and Death of Socrates</a></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Since you were in high school, you’ve probably heard about Socrates and his infamous &#39;Socratic Method.&#39;...
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="applied-socratic-method" scheme="https://ficons.fiction.com/categories/applied-socratic-method/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Karma Approach</title>
    <link href="https://ficons.fiction.com/2014/08/06/the-karma-approach/"/>
    <id>https://ficons.fiction.com/2014/08/06/the-karma-approach/</id>
    <published>2014-08-06T14:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-14T16:15:16.187Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Let me tell you about something I learned a long time ago that has made a big difference to me: Karma.<br><a id="more"></a><br>I don’t mean Karma in a religious or ethereal way either. I mean it in a way that makes a real impact on your work and the results you’ll see.</p><p>But first, a quick story…</p><h1 id="Discovering-Karma"><a href="#Discovering-Karma" class="headerlink" title="Discovering Karma"></a>Discovering Karma</h1><blockquote><p>“Again, you can’t connect the dots looking forward; you can only connect them looking backwards. So you have to trust that the dots will somehow connect in your future. You have to trust in something — your gut, destiny, life, karma, whatever. This approach has never let me down, and it has made all the difference in my life.” – Steve Jobs</p></blockquote><p>I discovered the concept of karma shortly after I graduated from graduate school. The time was around 2008 and if you remember, there were no jobs around, period. Especially no good jobs.</p><p>Because of this, I decided I would try and make ends meet by helping people build and market websites. Since I didn’t have a real portfolio, people weren’t exactly jumping to pay me lots to do this. Because of this, my first clients literally paid me near minimum wage to build and market their sites.</p><p>These weren’t great clients either. They obeyed the <strong>“inverse of client awesomeness to amount they’re paying you”</strong> law. Which basically means the less a client pays you, the worse and more demanding they usually are (many of you have probably seen this).</p><p>But although these clients were demanding, unappreciative and paying me almost nothing, I worked overtime to do a good job for them:</p><ul><li>I built them amazing websites;</li><li>I never left them hanging;</li><li>I never ignored them;</li><li>I never complained, asked for more money or gave them attitude.</li></ul><p>So why did I do all of this? Karma.</p><p>I knew, or trusted, that if I did a good job for even these crappy clients, somehow I would eventually be taken care of.</p><p>Sure enough, these clients were referring me to new clients. The new clients, stunned at the awesome reviews, were willing to pay me 5 times what I had been getting paid by the original clients.</p><p>Then before long, I had too many of these new clients, and my prices had to go up again. I was now comfortable in my income and everything was headed in the right direction.</p><p><a href="https://www.pagelines.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">PageLines</a> started much the same way. I gave away free web design tools and only started charging when they became too popular to support for free.</p><h1 id="Do-you-have-karma"><a href="#Do-you-have-karma" class="headerlink" title="Do you have karma?"></a>Do you have karma?</h1><p>After reading this, the importance of Karma may seem obvious. In real life it is anything but…</p><p>Here are some hallmarks that someone does NOT get karma:</p><ul><li>They say, “you get what you pay for.” Regarding their work;</li><li>They only work as hard as they are expected to work;</li><li>They give only superficial insights and keep any valuable knowledge to themselves;</li><li>They insist on “getting paid well” before proving themselves.</li></ul><p>The thing about true Karma behavior is that it’s non-obvious. It can actually be counterintuitive.</p><h1 id="How-YOU-should-think-about-Karma"><a href="#How-YOU-should-think-about-Karma" class="headerlink" title="How YOU should think about Karma"></a>How YOU should think about Karma</h1><p>What you need to do is ask yourself the following:</p><ul><li>Do I sincerely want to help others reach their goals?  Do I actually help them?</li><li>Do I do more than is expected for my cost?</li><li>Do I consistently go over and above without being forced?</li><li>Do I work hard to learn what I need to do to actually help?</li></ul><p>Here’s the point: doing these things might not seem to be in your interest in the short term, but karma is about faith.</p><p>I believe in Karma to the point where I’ve made it the #1 value of my company, PageLines. And here’s how we write it:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Karma Comes First</strong><br>When approaching new projects or initiatives; look to find ways of helping people – altruistic intent. If we are successful at helping the world, we will be taken care of. Reciprocation is the most powerful force on Earth.”</p></blockquote><p>Try Karma in your business, my guess is you’ll see results.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Let me tell you about something I learned a long time ago that has made a big difference to me:...
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="the-karma-approach" scheme="https://ficons.fiction.com/categories/the-karma-approach/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Picasso Method</title>
    <link href="https://ficons.fiction.com/2014/08/01/the-picasso-method/"/>
    <id>https://ficons.fiction.com/2014/08/01/the-picasso-method/</id>
    <published>2014-08-01T14:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-14T16:15:16.188Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ll start this article with a question: do you respect Picasso as an artist?</p><a id="more"></a><p>I once did, but today I appreciate Picasso more as an entrepreneur and businessman than an artist. (As an artist I actually think he was the ultimate sell out.)</p><p>Why? Well that’s the subject of this article. Today I’ll explain Picasso’s story and how you can use some of his techniques to sell your art and find ultimate success.</p><h1 id="The-“real”-story-of-Picasso"><a href="#The-“real”-story-of-Picasso" class="headerlink" title="The “real” story of Picasso"></a>The “real” story of Picasso</h1><p>Almost no one knows the real story behind how Picasso got his start. Well, it goes something like this…</p><p>When he was a young man he moved to Paris to chase his dream of being an artist. Like most artists, Picasso struggled to find a way to get people to pay for his art. Because of this he spent these early years nearly destitute in severe poverty. The wikipedia article on Picasso says that he actually burned some of his art to stay warm. He was the quintessential starving artist.</p><blockquote><p>“What would have become of us if Kahnweiler hadn’t had a business sense?” – Picasso</p></blockquote><p>Luckily about this time Picasso met a man named <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniel-Henry_Kahnweiler" target="_blank" rel="external">Daniel-Henry Kahnweiler</a>, who was a local art dealer in Paris and a business man.</p><p>Kahnweiler offered Picasso a deal. Specifically, he offered to buy all of Picasso’s pieces and even give him a place to sleep in the back of his gallery. He didn’t give Picasso much in terms of pay, the equivalent of today’s minimum wage, but at least Picasso was surviving from his art and so he was happy.</p><h1 id="Fabricating-The-“Picasso-Story”"><a href="#Fabricating-The-“Picasso-Story”" class="headerlink" title="Fabricating The “Picasso Story”"></a>Fabricating The “Picasso Story”</h1><blockquote><p>“Fake it ’til you make it.”</p></blockquote><p>As an art dealer, Kahnweiler had some very important insights into what makes someone buy a piece of art.</p><p>Kahnweiler knew that people don’t buy “art” at all. They buy a story and a brand; and maybe most importantly, people buy art as a status symbol.</p><p>So that’s what he tapped into.</p><p>While Picasso had been used to either giving his art away or selling it extremely cheap; Kahnweiler marked his art up to astronomical prices.</p><p>He fabricated a story to tell people about Picasso and let them know he was the “next big thing.” He created urgency by telling the buyer they would be missing a hell of an investment if they passed on the opportunity to buy a Picasso.</p><p>And while these original buyers were more or less duped; <strong>they actually did make a hell of an investment.</strong> As they say, “fake it til you make it.”</p><h1 id="Selling-Out"><a href="#Selling-Out" class="headerlink" title="Selling Out"></a>Selling Out</h1><p>One of Picasso’s 5-second “masterpieces” or mind hack. You decide.<br>Masterpiece or mind hack?<br>A couple of years ago, I went to look at an original Picasso for sale at a local art gallery.  The piece was for sale for only $1.3 million dollars; a hell of a deal for an original Picasso, I thought.</p><p><br><br><em>Masterpiece or mind hack?</em><br></p><p>The piece itself looked like it had been drawn by a kindergarten student with crayon in approximately 5 minutes. But hey, it was an original Picasso, right?</p><p>There was a roman number IV written on the piece. I asked the dealer what that meant, and she said “oh, that means this is the fourteenth piece Picasso did… <strong>that day.</strong>”</p><p>So I asked, “What? That day? How did Picasso make fourteen pieces of art in a day?” and the dealer responded, “Actually, later on in his career Picasso didn’t actually paint or draw most his pieces, he would do the original and have his apprentices emulate them, then he would sign them and sell them as his own. He would sometimes sign 30 pieces or more in a day.”</p><p>That’s when I realized that when Picasso got older, he became the ultimate sellout. He realized that people would pay crazy money for anything with an original Picasso signature on it, it didn’t matter what the content of the art was.</p><p>At this point Picasso ceased to be an artist, he became exclusively a businessman with a very lucrative brand.</p><h1 id="The-Moral-of-the-Story"><a href="#The-Moral-of-the-Story" class="headerlink" title="The Moral of the Story"></a>The Moral of the Story</h1><p>What can we learn from the story of Picasso?</p><p>Well, the most important take away is that people don’t buy art for the art. They buy the brand; or specifically, they will buy their perception of a brand. Often times they are buying that art as a status symbol they can use to subtly show off to their friends.. (“Wow, you have a Picasso?!” “Ohhh, the crayon and roman numeral IV in this piece just spoke to me and I had to have it.”)</p><p>As an artist, what does this mean for you?</p><ul><li><p><strong>Build a Recognizable Brand</strong><br>Create a focused brand and reinforce it in all your work. It doesn’t matter if you’re a painter, musician, dancer, etc.. you need a brand that you can build and imbue with meaning. For that, start by reading the Fiction article on </p></li><li><p><strong>Create A Story</strong><br>Any good brand in art has a story. It doesn’t have to be a great story, it just has to be one that others can tell about you.</p></li><li><strong>Fake It ‘Til You Make It</strong><br>Your gonna need to find a way to make people believe you are already a big deal, even when you’re just starting out. There are many ways of doing this. For another example of this, watch the <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1587707/" target="_blank" rel="external">Movie Exit Through the Gift Shop</a> by Banksy.</li><li><strong>Be Expensive</strong><br>In branding, we talk about price positioning a lot. Is your brand the cheap generic, or the expensive premium version. In art, you ALWAYS want to be positioned as an expensive product. Just by insisting on a high price, people will appreciate your art more and  will pay a lot more for it.</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      I’ll start this article with a question: do you respect Picasso as an artist?...
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="the-picasso-method" scheme="https://ficons.fiction.com/categories/the-picasso-method/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Social Media Rules</title>
    <link href="https://ficons.fiction.com/2014/07/28/social-media-rules/"/>
    <id>https://ficons.fiction.com/2014/07/28/social-media-rules/</id>
    <published>2014-07-28T14:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-14T16:15:16.181Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today’s post is a quick study on using Facebook for influencers (or those that desire to be). Note that these rules and observations likely apply elsewhere.</p><a id="more"></a><p>I’m writing this article for two reasons:</p><p>First, sites like Facebook are becoming a window to the world. If we want to keep and maintain a personal brand, then it’s important to follow some consistent good practices. These rules are not necessarily just for building your personal brand, but also to prevent you from screwing it up.</p><p>Second, without rules it’s hard to observe them. So even for myself, I wanted to write this so I had some guidelines!</p><h1 id="Rule-1-–-Get-a-good-profile-picture-keep-it-and-use-it-everywhere"><a href="#Rule-1-–-Get-a-good-profile-picture-keep-it-and-use-it-everywhere" class="headerlink" title="Rule 1 – Get a good profile picture, keep it, and use it everywhere."></a>Rule 1 – Get a good profile picture, keep it, and use it everywhere.</h1><blockquote><p>“Brand is just a perception, and perception will match reality over time.” – Elon Musk</p></blockquote><p>An important element of all branding is consistency and reinforcement. Profile pictures are synonymous with your online personal brand. Therefore, it makes sense to get a good one that reinforces your ‘image’. Then you’ll want to use it exclusively and consistently for a long time.</p><p>Why? Because over time this will reinforce your image and become a mnemonic people will associate with you.  If they see that picture they will know it’s you. So even if you’re not famous, maybe your profile picture can be.</p><h1 id="Rule-2-–-Post-content-people-actually-want-to-see"><a href="#Rule-2-–-Post-content-people-actually-want-to-see" class="headerlink" title="Rule 2 – Post content people actually want to see."></a>Rule 2 – Post content people actually want to see.</h1><p>I have some news for you. Your friends on Facebook probably don’t care about a lot of the important events in your life. And if these people are close enough to you to care, guess what? Facebook isn’t the medium.</p><p>So for that reason, stop posting the following type of posts:</p><ul><li>Couple photos</li><li>Pictures of food, drinking, and partying (unless it is part of your brand)</li><li>The same old ” you and a bunch of friends smiling and looking at the camera” shot</li><li>Baby or pregnant photos</li><li>Humble bragging and “I’m better than you” posts (discussed below)</li></ul><p>An influencer knows to post content people actually find educational, interesting, motivating or entertaining.</p><p>For that reason, here’s some formats that I find particularly good for building a personal brand:</p><ul><li><strong>Good quotes.</strong> Why? It’s always good to associate yourself with wisdom and people that are historic and well respected.</li><li><strong>Well done “selfies” or model shots.</strong> Yes, well done selfies are actually a good thing as long as they build and reinforce your  brand.</li><li><strong>Sharing articles with commentary.</strong></li><li><strong>Events and content that people can be part of.</strong>  If your followers can be part of something then it’s interesting to them. If they can’t, well then you’re just humble bragging.</li></ul><h1 id="Rule-3-–-Stop-the-humble-bragging-and-self-promotion"><a href="#Rule-3-–-Stop-the-humble-bragging-and-self-promotion" class="headerlink" title="Rule 3 – Stop the humble bragging and self promotion"></a>Rule 3 – Stop the humble bragging and self promotion</h1><p>One thing you should always remember is this general rule: <strong>Your friends do NOT want to see you more successful and happy than they are.</strong></p><p>This can be counterintuitive since, hey, these are your friends. But this is just psychology. Your friends, even your close ones, don’t want to see you elevated to a social status where they can’t keep up. Who can blame them? In fact, you probably feel the same way about your friends.</p><p>So considering that, here are the real reasons to avoid humble bragging and self promotion with your Facebook posts.</p><p><strong>It undermines your success.</strong> Real successful people don’t need to post their successes everywhere, other people do that for them.<br><strong>It makes people feel bad.</strong> Jealousy is not a good feeling to rouse in your friends and followers. It is the quickest way to get unfollowed.<br><strong>It doesn’t serve any real purpose.</strong> Think about it. What point does bragging and showing off on Facebook serve?</p><h1 id="Rule-4-–-Don’t-kick-the-hornet’s-nest"><a href="#Rule-4-–-Don’t-kick-the-hornet’s-nest" class="headerlink" title="Rule 4 – Don’t kick the hornet’s nest."></a>Rule 4 – Don’t kick the hornet’s nest.</h1><blockquote><p>“Never criticize, condemn, or complain.”</p></blockquote><p>If there is a rule that is more important than any other when dealing with people; it is to never to criticize, condemn, or complain (the 3 C’s).</p><p>I often see people taking sides on very divisive and controversial topics. Which is a form of condemnation of the opposing view.</p><p>For influencers, this can be one of the largest mistakes you can make. Why? Because it creates enemies.</p><p>For example, think homeless people are causing problems in San Francisco? Well, even if they are, you should NOT say anything; because there may be a liberal editor at a smear magazine that wants to make a controversial post for page views. (As one of my good friends just found out.)</p><p>The same thing goes for topics like feminism, religion, politics etc. Stay away. You have been warned.</p><h1 id="Rule-5-–-Create-Content-Build-Karma"><a href="#Rule-5-–-Create-Content-Build-Karma" class="headerlink" title="Rule 5 – Create Content, Build Karma"></a>Rule 5 – Create Content, Build Karma</h1><p>If you really are an influencer or you would like to become one, then it’s important to build karma and create content associated with your personal brand.</p><p>This can be done in many ways. For example, this is one of the reasons I write these blog posts every day, with the sincere desire to give my readers a competitive advantage. (FYI: Nothing is more satisfying than giving the people that believe in you a competitive edge!)</p><p>So you might want to think about creating your own content to post on Facebook. Just remember it’s all about karma. It has to create value, which means it should be educational, interesting, motivating or entertaining.</p><h1 id="Anything-else"><a href="#Anything-else" class="headerlink" title="Anything else?"></a>Anything else?</h1><p>Would seriously like to hear if you have other tips and insights about using Facebook in the comments!</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Today’s post is a quick study on using Facebook for influencers (or those that desire to be). Note that these...
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="social-media-rules" scheme="https://ficons.fiction.com/categories/social-media-rules/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Secret To Productivity</title>
    <link href="https://ficons.fiction.com/2014/07/24/the-secret-to-productivity/"/>
    <id>https://ficons.fiction.com/2014/07/24/the-secret-to-productivity/</id>
    <published>2014-07-24T14:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-14T16:15:16.190Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the last few years, I’ve fallen in and out of love with work. After years of hitting it hard, I admit that last year I did experience some burnout and frustration.<a id="more"></a></p><p>However, today I’m happy to say things are different. All because of a change I made a few months ago.</p><p>Here I’m going to explain to you the simple, and ridiculously powerful, concept which brought me back. Now I’m more productive and passionate about my work than I’ve been for years.</p><h1 id="The-Backstory"><a href="#The-Backstory" class="headerlink" title="The Backstory"></a>The Backstory</h1><p>I’d say that my experience running PageLines has been unique. Within a year of being founded, <a href="https://www.pagelines.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">PageLines</a> went from being a small web marketing consultancy to a one-person software company doing over a million dollars in revenue. While this was a very fun experience, more than anything it was stressful.</p><p>During this period, we were doing roughly 40 new paying customers per day, and I was clearly underwater. Inevitably, some customers weren’t getting the desired experience and we were leaving tons of opportunities on the table.</p><p>Around this time I decided to move to San Francisco, because “that’s what software companies do…” Even though I love that city, it was never best for my productivity or business objectives. To be specific, I was never able to get on top of things the way I wanted.</p><p>So last year I experienced burnout. Something which I feel every entrepreneur should go through and plan on.</p><p>I was simply unmotivated; and this was a very unproductive time for me regarding work.  My schedule went like this: get up, work on ‘whatever‘, go to event/party/meeting, go to bed (at some point).</p><p>It doesn’t take a genius to see that my schedule made me very distracted and unfocused. It also prevented me from thinking clearly and getting quality work done within a reasonable time frame.</p><p>A couple months ago I decided that I needed to change something and get back on track. That’s when I re-read a favorite book of mine, and had an idea…</p><h1 id="The-Original-Self-Help-Book"><a href="#The-Original-Self-Help-Book" class="headerlink" title="The Original Self Help Book"></a>The Original Self Help Book</h1><blockquote><p>“every part of my business should have its allotted time.”</p></blockquote><p>Benjamin Franklin is probably my most admired public figure. Years ago I read his autobiography and felt it was so interesting, that I’ve sought to emulate his life ever since.</p><p>So when I was looking for answers, I actually re-read this book and had a revelation.</p><p>At one point, Ben recounts how powerful his concept of ‘order’ was. Defining it as <em>“every part of my business should have its allotted time.”</em></p><p>He then scheduled his day to the minute regarding what he should be working on, when he should go to bed, wake up etc..</p><p>When I first read this book, I took this idea and said ‘that’s interesting’ and kept reading. But after rereading it, that’s when it finally sunk in.</p><p>Specifically, I realized that structuring your day gives you a benchmark to judge yourself against. It’s not enough just to think about it, you actually have to write it down in concrete terms.</p><p></p><p><br><br><em>Ben Franklin’s Daily Schedule</em></p><p></p><h1 id="My-Concrete-Daily-Routine"><a href="#My-Concrete-Daily-Routine" class="headerlink" title="My Concrete Daily Routine"></a>My Concrete Daily Routine</h1><blockquote><p>“If you don’t know where you’re going; you probably won’t get there.”</p></blockquote><p>So that’s it, that is my #1 secret to productivity. Setting a daily routine, in writing, that accounts for all the various things that can come up in a week.</p><p>The schedule should take into account:</p><ul><li>Week days vs. week ends</li><li>Vacation schedule</li><li>What and when you eat &amp; drink</li><li>When to workout, shower, read, write, work, etc. etc..</li></ul><p>Here’s my basic daily process (which I keep in Evernote):</p><ul><li><strong>Basic Structure</strong><ul><li>Early Morning: stretch, eat, coffee, plan resolutions for the day</li><li>Morning Work: production (process, writing and composition).</li><li>Lunch: eat, check accounts, email, and social media</li><li>Afternoons: analysis, management, and meetings.</li><li>Early evening: errands, sports/workout then dinner, Email/messages</li><li>Evenings: Conversation, Research &amp; Study (no drinking during the week</li><li>Before bed: Organize, stretch, and shower</li><li>Weekends<ul><li>Do sports one day (minimum)</li></ul></li></ul></li><li><strong>Resolutions:</strong> <em>Include general resolutions including:</em><ul><li>Time for family,</li><li>Don’t drink during the week. If you do, drink a glass of red wine or soda water with a splash of whiskey.</li><li>Have good &amp; focused workouts (carry a notepad).</li><li>Use a schedule to plan afternoons and mornings.</li><li>Never get over intoxicated.</li><li>7AM. Wake up at the same time every day, regardless of bed time.</li><li>Don’t use the snooze button. Don’t start the day with a failure.</li><li>Don’t get caught out, if you go somewhere late likely you’ll get stuck.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Week days</strong><ul><li>Monday: coordination meetings, 80/20 priority setting.</li><li>Tuesday: The best day for releasing new products and media. This gives the opportunity for final coordination and a remaining week for the work to be absorbed and responded to.</li><li>Wednesday: The best day for group meetings and education.</li><li>Thursday: Ideal for events and more social get togethers, since there is no competition with the weekend.</li><li>Friday: Best day for reflection and goal review.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Questions</strong><ul><li><em>When to shower: morning or night?</em><ul><li>Showering is a necessary task daily. However, we have the option of showering in the morning/night or another time during the day.</li><li>Since we are working out in evening, we may need showers after workout or before bed or both.</li><li>We should keep them short. Shave, soap, shampoo, rinse.</li></ul></li><li><em>What time to go to bed? How much sleep?</em><ul><li>Should be working by 8am</li><li>Up by 7am, means 11pm bedtime or less than 8 hours of sleep</li></ul></li><li><em>High leverage activities, when to plan them and add them to schedule?<ul><li>Reserve morning time (8am to Noon) for production as usual.</li></ul></em></li><li><em>Evening Parties and weekends?</em><ul><li>Typical bed time will be 2am</li><li>Drink only wine as drinking often detracts from the following day</li><li>Wake up at 10am</li><li>10am to noon: breakfast, socializing.</li><li>Noon to 6pm: activity (planned earlier in the week).</li><li>6pm to 8pm: social dinner.</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><p>Now, I don’t always obey this schedule exactly (although I try). But having this allows me to see exactly how far from the goal I am. For example, if I wake up an hour late, I can figure out why and try and improve.</p><h1 id="Do-this-it’s-more-important-than-you-think"><a href="#Do-this-it’s-more-important-than-you-think" class="headerlink" title="Do this, it’s more important than you think!"></a>Do this, it’s more important than you think!</h1><p>You’re probably sitting there thinking, “Ah, that’s neat. Hmmm… what should I do for lunch.”  In other words, you’re not actually gonna do this. Why? Because you are underestimating its importance.</p><p>Take it from me and my homeboy Ben, it will do more for you than you think! Time to get writing.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Over the last few years, I’ve fallen in and out of love with work. After years of hitting it hard,...
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="the-secret-to-productivity" scheme="https://ficons.fiction.com/categories/the-secret-to-productivity/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The 21 Laws Of Good Copywriting</title>
    <link href="https://ficons.fiction.com/2014/07/23/the-21-laws-of-good-copywriting/"/>
    <id>https://ficons.fiction.com/2014/07/23/the-21-laws-of-good-copywriting/</id>
    <published>2014-07-23T14:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-14T16:15:16.181Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over my years in the internet business, I’ve had a lot of practice with copywriting. In that time, I’ve created some rules which I think will help you write better marketing copy.</p><a id="more"></a><p>In my opinion, some of these “laws” are non-obvious, so my goal is that even experienced copywriters will learn something from this guide.  Newer writers will get a strong framework to build from.</p><p>First, why are these laws important?</p><blockquote><p>“Worry not that no one knows of you; seek to be worth knowing.” – Confucius</p></blockquote><p>Copywriting is much more that simply writing to convince people to buy your product. You can use it to do things which are much more powerful.</p><p><em>Good copy lets you:</em></p><ul><li>Build a tribe / following</li><li>Create loyal customers that love your brand</li><li>Create a feeling of kinship in the reader</li><li>Start a movement or new trend</li></ul><p>And these laws are also needed to prevent the effects of bad copy (which I’ve had to learn the hard way).</p><p><em>Bad copy can easily let you be perceived as:</em></p><ul><li>Greedy</li><li>Arrogant</li><li>Inexperienced</li><li>Boring</li></ul><p>Ok, so now hopefully  you get the point. Let’s get into the 21 Laws of Good Copywriting…</p><h2 id="The-21-Laws-of-Good-Copywriting"><a href="#The-21-Laws-of-Good-Copywriting" class="headerlink" title="The 21 Laws of Good Copywriting"></a>The 21 Laws of Good Copywriting</h2><ol><li><p><strong>The First Rule: Always Be Human</strong></p><ul><li>Act and write as a human would. If saying something out loud would sound out of context, arrogant, stiff/corporate, boring, then you are not doing good copywriting.</li><li>For example, a human would never say “Buy this now!” they would say, “Check this out, we think you’ll like it.“</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Assign ownership to the reader</strong></p><ul><li>Maximize the words “You”, “Your”</li><li>Never user “I”, “we”, or “our”. Using self-centered language like “I” and “we” gives the impression that you only care about yourself or your business/solutions rather than the customer.</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Provide explanation</strong></p><ul><li>Use the word ‘because’ often, because it gives context and explanation.</li><li>Imagine every point you make followed by the question Why? in the customers mind.</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Avoid the cliche’</strong></p><ul><li>Endeavor to entertain, write uniquely yet simply.</li><li>Cliche copywriting is comparable to the stock images of business people giving each other high five.</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Never, ever, mention competition by name</strong></p><ul><li>Speaking badly about the competition will always make you look bad instead.</li><li>Usually seen as arrogant</li><li>What To do instead: Discuss the competitive approach or category and why it might not be right for the reader</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Don’t use the word “very”</strong></p><ul><li>Why? Unoriginal. Use the extreme form of the word instead.</li><li>Example: instead of ‘very tired’ use ‘exhausted‘, instead of ‘very cold’ use ‘freezing’ and so on…</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Start sentences with Verbs and Active Voice</strong></p><ul><li>If you’re struggling on starting a sentence, then follow this rule: add power to your sentences by starting them with verbs.</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Don’t use exclamation points!</strong></p><ul><li>Exclamation points are often be seen as trying to hard, yelling or selling (as in used car selling). Good writing doesn’t do any of these. In my opinion, exclamation points are for use by experts only.</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Use “advanced” punctuation</strong></p><ul><li>What I call “advanced” punctuation allows you to be read in a way that is closer to your intent (and also makes you look smart).</li><li>For example, use m-dashes–they’re great for asides–and semi-colons; they are nice for combining closely related sentences.</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Different Headline Styles are OK</strong></p><ul><li>There are different formats for headings and titles. Using a full sentence is okay and good style (used by Apple). These should be formatted with Capitalized first letter and period.</li><li>Example: “[Whatever] for the rest of us.”</li><li>If not a sentence, use all caps except for common connecting words like ‘the’, ‘as’, ‘in’ and ‘of’.</li><li>Example: Build the Best Websites in the World</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>And old preposition rules can be broken</strong></p><ul><li>They say don’t start or end a sentence with a preposition. It’s ok to do this, it adds a conversational tone and shows you’re not afraid to break some rules.</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Icons, images, and media are copy</strong></p><ul><li>These days icons, images and media are very important to copy. People have short attention spans and need to be persuaded quickly. Learn basic graphic design and how and when to use these formats.</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Never compliment yourself</strong></p><ul><li>One of the most common mistakes by beginning (and sometimes advanced) writers is complimenting yourself.</li><li>For example, “join the amazing community” is a form of complimenting yourself and the community.</li><li>Instead compliment what it will do for the reader: ““Join this community which will help you to do amazing things.”</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Be inclusive, don’t use the word “our”</strong></p><ul><li>You always want to instill a feeling of kinship or ownership in the part of the reader.</li><li>Instead of using the word “our” you should usually be using the word “your” instead.</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Use bulleted lists Often</strong></p><ul><li>Use bulleted lists as often as possible. They provide the reader a clear way of seeing differing points or attributes.</li><li>They also increase the speed at which a reader can scan your copy.</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Don’t use fluff, shorter is better</strong></p><ul><li>Remove wording that is overly descriptive, complimentary or trying too hard.</li><li>People have an adverse reaction when they notice pointless or redundant text.</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Don’t try too hard</strong></p><ul><li>Why? Trying to hard makes people feel like they are being sold, which makes them feel like they are not getting a good deal.</li><li>Your attitude should NOT be: “Try this super cool widget, it’s amazing and will change your life forever OMG!”</li><li>Your attitude should be “Here’s what we’ve got for you, we think it will help you with your goals. Try it, we’d love to be a part of your success.”</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Use humor and jokes</strong></p><ul><li>Don’t be boring. Add jokes and other humor to your writing as you might in a conversation. (Copywriting isn’t boring right?)</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>The best copywriting is education</strong></p><ul><li>Steve Jobs used to say “the best marketing is education.” This applies fully to copywriting. Speak as if you’re advising someone on a purchase or action, educate them to the features and tradeoffs.</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Use the correct format for the job</strong></p><ul><li>There are four stages reader go through as they are reading copy: A-I-D-A. You always want to use the correct communication format for each…</li></ul><ol><li><strong>Awareness</strong> – Landing page format. Use the 3 second rule: “Let the know what you do and how it can help them within 3 seconds”</li><li><strong>Interested</strong> – Use product tours, media, comparison tables. Help people understand where your product fits in the world.</li><li><strong>Decision</strong> – Use long format text and stories. Make the user feel safe and that there is a safety net for any decisions they make.</li><li><strong>Action</strong> – This is where you take money or information from users. Remove all distractions and guide them through each step.</li></ol></li><li><p><strong>Even the best rules are meant to be broken</strong></p><ul><li>As they say, to be an artist you need to learn the rules in order to break them.</li><li>Except for these laws, never break these ;)</li></ul></li></ol>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      Over my years in the internet business, I’ve had a lot of practice with copywriting. In that time, I’ve created...
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="the-21-laws-of-good-copywriting" scheme="https://ficons.fiction.com/categories/the-21-laws-of-good-copywriting/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Davinci Method</title>
    <link href="https://ficons.fiction.com/2014/07/21/the-davinci-method/"/>
    <id>https://ficons.fiction.com/2014/07/21/the-davinci-method/</id>
    <published>2014-07-21T14:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-14T16:15:16.186Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few years ago I began to realize the importance of communication and proper research in business. During this time I studied many techniques and books. <a id="more"></a> However, more than any other Leonardo DaVinci, gave me an important revelation that I still use to this day.</p><p>I believe this technique is one of the secret’s to being an innovator. The advantages of the following technique are the following:</p><ul><li>Better Cognition</li><li>Enhanced Ability to Innovate</li><li>Better research and exposure to ideas</li></ul><h2 id="DaVinci’s-Notes"><a href="#DaVinci’s-Notes" class="headerlink" title="DaVinci’s Notes"></a>DaVinci’s Notes</h2><blockquote><p>“However, that’s when I realized that the fact that these notes existed, and that they were so detailed, was a revelation in itself.”</p></blockquote><p>One day I made a spontaneous purchase of a large coffee table size book filled with all of Leonardo’s notes. These notes have become quite famous for their artistic value, and I was hoping that Leo would drop some insights.</p><p>On first reading it, I didn’t notice too many things that stood out in terms of knowledge.  Most Leo’s insights were simply outdated.</p><p>However, that’s when I realized that the fact that these notes existed, and that they were so detailed, was a revelation in itself.</p><p>How many people today do such meticulous research and study?</p><p>So after realizing this, and studying DaVinci’s approach, I created what I call “The DaVinci Method” for research and note taking.</p><h2 id="DaVinci-Method"><a href="#DaVinci-Method" class="headerlink" title="DaVinci Method"></a>DaVinci Method</h2><h3 id="The-Technique"><a href="#The-Technique" class="headerlink" title="The Technique"></a>The Technique</h3><p>If you take a look at DaVinci’s notes, he always used plain pieces of paper and filled them up with notes in an unformatted way. He would do detailed sketches and fill every page up with insights in his notes. Based on this, here are some rules on taking notes…</p><ul><li><strong>Take Notes</strong> – Most importantly you should have a notebook that you keep with you all the time. Compliment this by using Evernote to keep track in an electronic format.</li><li><strong>Draw Pictures</strong> – Drawing pictures and 3-d forms is better than text only. This is because our memory works better when it can associate information with objects.</li><li><strong>Don’t Format</strong> – Don’t buy notebooks with lines on the pages. Keep the notes unformatted and allow your mind to freely structure the information on the page.</li><li><strong>Write Down Everything</strong> – When studying something, you may feel that a particular observation is obvious or not worth writing down. These cases can in fact be the most important thing to document, since people often over estimate their ability to remember things.</li></ul><p><br><br><em>Example of DaVinci’s Note Taking</em><br></p><h3 id="The-Process"><a href="#The-Process" class="headerlink" title="The Process"></a>The Process</h3><p>For every subject DaVinci wanted to master, he went through the same steps. I believe this gave him a formatted way to get access to all the good ideas related to a subject, so he could then compare and contrast them.</p><ul><li><strong>Theory</strong> – Studying theory (e.g. books) will teach you the basics and give you the perspective to understand subtlety in the work of others (competition and masters)</li><li><strong>Masters</strong> – Provided you have perspective from ‘theory’… Studying those who have ‘mastered’ a subject will show you the best ideas to employ in that subject.</li><li><strong>Competition</strong> – Once you are aware of theory and best practice, studying competition will show you how ideas can be applied to a situation relevant to your own.</li><li><strong>Get Feedback</strong> – Gaining objective feedback from respected colleagues will give you the ability to see in your own work, what others do. Feedback works in concert with your perspective on a subject. All feedback should be reflected on; although not all should be used.</li></ul><p>Here is a quote from DaVinci on taking feedback on your work:</p><blockquote><p>“Be curious to hear with patience the opinions of others. Consider and weigh well whether those who find fault have ground or not for blame, and if so, amend. But if not, make as though you have not heard, or if they should be someone you esteem, show them by arguments the cause of their mistake.”</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      A few years ago I began to realize the importance of communication and proper research in business. During this time...
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="the-davinci-method" scheme="https://ficons.fiction.com/categories/the-davinci-method/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Naming Your Company</title>
    <link href="https://ficons.fiction.com/2014/07/18/naming-your-company/"/>
    <id>https://ficons.fiction.com/2014/07/18/naming-your-company/</id>
    <published>2014-07-18T14:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-14T16:15:16.180Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the first subjects I want to cover here on Fiction is the dynamics and principles around creating a great name for a company or brand. <a id="more"></a> This is something I spend a lot of time explaining to people.</p><p>The first thing to know about naming is that there are a lot of red herrings and places to go wrong. I’m not sure why there is so much misinformation out there, but in this guide we will go through all of these potential pitfalls, and point you in the right direction.</p><p>Here are the golden, immutable, principles of naming…</p><h2 id="Principle-1-–-Naming-is-not-a-group-activity"><a href="#Principle-1-–-Naming-is-not-a-group-activity" class="headerlink" title="Principle #1 – Naming is not a group activity."></a>Principle #1 – Naming is not a group activity.</h2><p>There are many nuances to naming a business. It’s an art. This is why you should never try and name something with a group of people. One person, with a solid knowledge of branding and naming dynamics, should present some solid options from the rest to pick from.</p><p>If you attempt to name something with a group you will end up with the blandest, most typical, boring name. Simply because groups tend to remove the edge and move towards conformity. Also, the other members of the group may not be familiar with naming pitfalls and will argue with you endlessly about some of the following points…</p><h2 id="Principle-2-–-A-good-name-does-NOT-explain-what-you-do"><a href="#Principle-2-–-A-good-name-does-NOT-explain-what-you-do" class="headerlink" title="Principle #2 – A good name does NOT explain what you do."></a>Principle #2 – A good name does NOT explain what you do.</h2><p>Many first time entrepreneurs think that a brand name should somehow explain what there company does subtly. As an example, My company <a href="http://www.pagelines.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">PageLines</a>, has products that compete in the WordPress theme world.  Nearly EVERY company in this business has fallen for this trap. Some top of mind examples:</p><ul><li>WPEngine</li><li>ThemeForest</li><li>WooThemes</li><li>Elegant Themes</li><li>Press75</li><li>WPZoom</li><li>Themify</li><li>VPThemes</li><li>ThemeFurnace</li><li>Theme Foundry</li><li>ThemeZen</li><li>….And i could go on for at least another 100 companies.</li></ul><p>These type of names are called “descriptive” names and there are many large downsides to them. This naming strategy will always tax your marketing budget because the brands are pulled from a small group of keywords hence they blend together. Ultimately, you end up spending your advertising dollars building the brands you’ve incorporated into your name (in this case WordPress). This makes descriptive names are the opposite of good marketing. Other reasons they’re bad:</p><ul><li>They’re boring</li><li>They’re unoriginal</li><li>They have no personality</li><li>You can’t build brand awareness</li><li>Undifferentiated from competition</li></ul><h3 id="Pitfalls"><a href="#Pitfalls" class="headerlink" title="Pitfalls"></a>Pitfalls</h3><p>So why do people fall for this? Here are the common pitfalls”</p><ul><li><p><strong>How will people know what we do if it’s not in the name?</strong> Your company name will always be presented with context. For example, if Google had named themselves GreatSearchEngine, then a journalist writing about the company would have to say something like this.. “Today, we’re writing about GreatSearchEngine, they are a… um, great search engine for searching the web.” See? That’s redundant.</p></li><li><p><strong>When can this work?</strong><br>Descriptive naming can be a good strategy when you want do deflect brand awareness towards a parent brand. For example, Facebook seems to be using this strategy with their apps, using descriptive names like Messenger and Pages, etc.., which focus you on the parent Facebook brand instead.</p></li></ul><h2 id="Principle-3-–-Don’t-negatively-break-down-a-name"><a href="#Principle-3-–-Don’t-negatively-break-down-a-name" class="headerlink" title="Principle #3 – Don’t negatively break down a name"></a>Principle #3 – Don’t negatively break down a name</h2><p>Another common mistake in branding is to take every name candidate and break it down, trying to think of every possible negative connotation the name can have with customers.  This is a mistake because customers never take a company name and dissect it for negative meaning. To a customer, they use the name to understand a brand’s personality and build up from there.  For example, if I suggested I wanted to name a new airline something like… oh, Virgin, here’s what a naming committee might say:</p><ul><li>Virgin Airlines?<ul><li>People will think we are new at this, and that’s not what we want!</li><li>People will think we’re a sex toy company</li><li>That name nothing to do with flying</li></ul></li></ul><p>Now clearly, the reality is that Virgin is one of the most admired and recognized brands in the space. So all those people would have been wrong.</p><p>A brand name should simply represent the personality of a company. In Virgin’s case, the brand exemplifies ‘sexy’ (as they hire lots of attractive flight attendants!) so it’s a perfect fit.</p><h2 id="Principle-4-–-Don’t-choose-a-name-because-you-can-get-the-com-but-think-about-the-trademark"><a href="#Principle-4-–-Don’t-choose-a-name-because-you-can-get-the-com-but-think-about-the-trademark" class="headerlink" title="Principle #4 – Don’t choose a name because you can get the .com (but think about the trademark)"></a>Principle #4 – Don’t choose a name because you can get the .com (but think about the trademark)</h2><p>Seems pretty straightforward, but over the last 20 or so years, there have been many-a-company named simply because the domain name was available. Even I fell for this trap with my first company the admittedly poorly named, eDoctr.</p><p>People make this mistake because they want people to easily be able to get to the website.</p><p>The reality is that, yes, it’s always nice to have a nice domain name but it is exponentially more important to have a solid brand than a good domain.</p><p>My suggestion is that you choose a good brand, and then find a clever domain that makes sense around that brand. For example, for <a href="https://fromfiction.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Fiction</a>, I was able to get <a href="https://fromfiction.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">FromFiction.com</a> which is almost as good!  Also you can consider .io or .co domain names as well. Like Angel.co for AngelList; which is solid!</p><p>One caveat is that you definitely <em>should</em> pay attention to trademark right as this has legal implications. Simply, if you choose the same name as someone else in your space, that is a deal killer. A quick Google search for the [name] +</p><p>should let you know if you’ll have a problem.</p><h2 id="Principle-5-–-The-best-names-are-two-syllables-long-and-easy-to-spell-phonetically"><a href="#Principle-5-–-The-best-names-are-two-syllables-long-and-easy-to-spell-phonetically" class="headerlink" title="Principle #5 – The best names are two syllables long and easy to spell (phonetically)"></a>Principle #5 – The best names are two syllables long and easy to spell (phonetically)</h2><p>This one is basic psychology. People tend to build basic schemas for things that make them easier to say, spell, and remember.  Because of this, people naturally gravitate towards brands that have low cognitive load (how’s that for a first principle?).</p><p>So when it comes to phonetics, that is, how your brand sounds when it’s said out loud, it’s important it has only two syllables, at least, as pronounced. For example, do you ever wonder why we call Los Angeles, “LA”; but we never call New York, “NY”? This is because people tend to want to shorten things to two syllables. The same goes for one syllable brands, people tend to lengthen those. So you might see many one syllable brands get the ‘.com’ thrown in with the brand for this reason (e.g. Moz.com instead of just Moz).</p><p>Some brands like Amazon or my friend Maren’s company, Zirtual, are technically more than two syllables; however, when they are said out loud they are typically pronounced with two syllables. Try it! Amazon is typical said “Am-Zon” and Zirtual “Zirch-ul”.. neat concept huh?</p><p>The same goes for spelling, people want names that are easy to spell and type on a keyboard.  You may want to do some testing regarding this. Ask people to spell the name, if most can’t on the first try, then you probably want to keep looking.  Try typing the name, make sure it’s not awkward and you can do it fast, this might be for your own benefit as much as your customers!</p><h2 id="Principle-6-–-Name-to-represent-a-brand’s-hence-company’s-personality"><a href="#Principle-6-–-Name-to-represent-a-brand’s-hence-company’s-personality" class="headerlink" title="Principle #6 – Name to represent a brand’s (hence company’s) personality."></a>Principle #6 – Name to represent a brand’s (hence company’s) personality.</h2><p>Over time your name tends to help shape the personality of your company’s brand and hence its culture, values, and more. This again underlines why the name is so important.  Here are some examples of this:</p><ul><li>Apple: Human</li><li>Virgin:  Sexy, Youthful</li><li>Google: Playful</li><li>Twitter: Playful, child-like</li><li>Microsoft: evil corporate empire (lol)</li></ul><p>In my case, I’ve always thought <a href="https://www.pagelines.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">PageLines</a> had a sophisticated, and clean personality. If it was a person it would be a young designer. <a href="http://fromfiction.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Fiction</a> would be somewhere in the same area. <a href="https://soundcloud.com/sxgnals" target="_blank" rel="external">The Signals</a>, my other brand, is for electronic so it’s meant to have the personality of a dystopian future, or something along those lines haha..</p><h2 id="Anything-I-missed"><a href="#Anything-I-missed" class="headerlink" title="Anything I missed?"></a>Anything I missed?</h2><p>Hopefully the above principles help you on your way to naming a company. Would love to debate the points or add/edit in additional context for you guys. Please feel free to add to the conversation.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      One of the first subjects I want to cover here on Fiction is the dynamics and principles around creating a...
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="naming-your-company" scheme="https://ficons.fiction.com/categories/naming-your-company/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
